Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
The moment this diary
bursts into flames
and turns to ash...
That would mean
you failed your mission.
To save Juanito.
Is it because
Does that mean
Juanito's still alive?
I swear we won't cause
any more trouble.
We won't show
our faces here.
There is only one way
for you to be
with your husband.
And that is death.
Carmelita...
Sonya?
Josefina? Josefina!
Josefina!
- Hindi!
- Josefina!
- My poor daughter!
You need to marry Leandro.
If not, all I worked hard for
will be for nothing.
What Carmelita would
remember once she wakes up...
will be the time
before she met Juanito.
But it will only happen
if you succeed in your mission.
Mother, who is your guest?
Mr. Valdez.
What are you doing here?
He's here to tell you something.
About Juanito.
It's true
that we planned the attack
on San Alfonso's plaza.
It's true that Juanito was the mastermind.
But...
He has nothing to do
with the death of Josefina.
Juanito would never hurt innocent people.
Especially Josefina
who became close to him.
We were all shocked.
Most especially Catapang.
When we heard
that Mr. Raul stabbed Josefina.
Our main objective
with the attack
was to create a diversion.
And kill
Gobernadorcillo Flores who was also present
at the plaza that night.
We believe
that
it was only
Mr. Raul's personal grudge against
Don Alejandro.
Which is why
he hurt
Josefina.
Now,
I'm afraid...
That...
That they would not relent
on torturing Juanito in prison.
Mister...
What can I do?
Juanito is important
to Catapang because he is an Alfonso.
Many joined our group
when they heard the news
that Juanito also joined the rebel forces.
Mother Olivia.
Is there a problem?
Did something happen?
I heard that
they're planning to execute Juanito.
On the 7th of December.
It's the 5th of December today.
How can they execute him
without even trying his case at court?
In Juanito's case,
a trial might not be needed at all.
Because it's clear that he's a rebel.
The reason
his execution was delayed...
Was...
Was because Judge Fernandez was hoping
Juanito would reveal
where the rebels are hiding.
But Juanito didn't say a word.
I visited Juanito earlier.
And I learned
that he knows where Eduardo and Maria are.
Are you sure aboout that, Mother Olivia?
Where are they?
He wasn't able to tell me because
the guards had arrived.
They stopped our conversation.
Catapang will make a plan
to rescue Juanito out of prison.
But Catapang was not
made aware of my intentions
here with you because...
His disdain towards
your family is quite great.
But...
I need your help,
Carmelita.
Daughter,
Juanito is our only hope of finding Maria.
I want to help as well.
Mister,
how can I help?
First,
we need to convince
Judge Fernandez
to use
Carmelita.
In order to
extract information
from Juanito
about the rebels' whereabouts.
It's uncertain,
but this is our only hope.
We got Judge Fernandez
to agree to our plan.
and proceeded to Fort Santiago.
But as soon as we got to Juanito's cell,
everything fell to pieces.
Let's stop the act!
I will give you one last chance, Juanito!
Tell me where the rebels are hiding!
You tricked me!
Juanito!
Let's go.
Stop!
Mother!
Let's get out of here!
Your escape is vital, Juanito!
Mother!
I'm sorry, Mother.
I'm sorry...
By the way...
This was found
in Doña Soledad's belongings.
My beloved daughter,
if you are reading this,
that means I am no longer in this world.
I have read your diary.
I know your true identity.
Despite that,
I will forever love you
as if you were my own.
I hope you would succeed in your mission
and wish happiness for you and Juanito.
Your mother,
Soledad Montecarlos.
You may go home, Carmelita.
Mother Olivia took the
fall for what happened.
And because of that...
She was sentenced to death.
Mother Olivia is the only one who knows
what I'm truly going through.
I can't lose her too!
Don't worry about me, Carmela.
I have been alive for so long.
Before God even created humans.
What do you mean?
I am an angel, Carmela.
My name is Faida.
It means
"folded wings."
I have three rewards
that I could give.
Once I've used that up...
I can vanish from this world.
I gave the first one
when I fell in love with a mortal.
I used the first wish
to return him back from the dead.
I gave the second one...
To Carmelita.
Mother Olivia...
May I
use the last one?
I want to know who killed Juanito.
Only you can find out who it was.
But I will give you a hint.
That person is just around here.
Watching everything you do.
You need to leave.
No... Mother Olivia!
Mother Olivia... wait a minute...
Mother...
Carmela,
before I go,
I want to share with you
the story of my first love.
I fell in love with hi
when he saved a child.
It was also his kindness that
led to him being shot and killed.
I gave him my First Wish
in order to revive him.
Even at the cost of my form changing.
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Olivia...
Valentino...
Mother Olivia left me with
the memory of her first love.
She taught me that
despite the noise and chaos,
there is nothing two lovers can't do.
Esmeralda!
This is the first time I saw a
necklace made from wood.
I'll keep this for now, alright?
Princess!
Who the hell are you?!
Don't you recognize me?
I'm Mercedes.
The poor girl whom you once played with.
I was with my sister, Cristeta back then.
But because we're dirt-poor,
your father forbade you to befriend us.
Carding!
What's the update?
Catapang!
Our attack was successful.
Theresita...
Don't get your hopes up
about Mr. Juanito's love.
Catapang wants him to end up with Mercedes
and continue leading the group.
Don Alejandro may have killed my father...
But that doesn't give me
the right to hate you, Miss.
Because he was also
the reason for the death of Miss Josefina.
Juanito...
I am thankful you are still alive.
You have nothing to be thankful for.
I need to live to end the misery
your family inflicted on us.
Carding!
get that woman.
- Juanito...
- Help me.
Wait -
Stand up!
- Where are you taking me?! Juanito!
- Come with us!
- Where are you taking me?!
- Just come with us!
Juanito! Where the
hell are you taking me?!
- Just come with us already!
- Help me, please!
Juanito!
Where are you taking me?!
Stop!
The Spanish were cruel to me.
They used me...
To cover up their corruption.
My sister-in-law asked for your help...
To inform your father
about their hardships due to unfair wages.
Mang Nestor was Catapang's brother!
What would your father feel...
when I send him your severed head?
So that he may feel the pain
of his deeds.
The killing
of my brother
and his whole family!
Father didn't order the
murder of Trinidad's family.
Don't defend your father!
Maybe it's right for you to die.
As payment for his sins to me!
Uncle!
Our comrades are here!
I miss you all so much...
I miss my sisters.
I miss...
I miss my grandmother.
My hunch was correct.
You have fever.
This is effective for cough,
runny nose, and headache.
This herb. Use it.
Why are you even helping me?
Are you messing with my head?
I'm just helping you.
Aren't you supposed to be mad at me?
Aren't you supposed to hate my family?
Aren't you happier here?
Aren't you happier with Mercedes?
Just leave me alone.
And don't ever help me anymore.
You can count on it.
I will never bother you again.
If that is what you want.
Help! Help!
Please help us! It's Mercedes!
Come help us!
Mercedes?
Mercedes.
Juanito...
Let her down!
Assist her!
Mercedes?
What happened?!
We were doing laundry at the river
when Don Alejandro suddenly came.
And General Leandro...
He was looking for his daughter.
- He even showed Carmelita's photo.
- Mercedes?
But then, General Leandro saw Mercedes
wearing Carmelita's necklace.
Andoy helped us escape,
but Mercedes still got shot.
I didn't know that...
this will be the consequence of taking
Carmelita's necklace.
Now I know.
That I can never
get the things not meant for me
no matter how much I desire them.
Mercedes?
Cut off that woman's head!
Juanito, no!
And send it to her father!
Juanito?
I should've killed you back then!
Carding!
Juanito!
Just go, Carmelita.
- Go straight to that path!
- No, no!
- There's a river there!
- No!
- Once you cross you'll find...
- Juanito, I'm not leaving you here!
- You'll find the guard's camp across!
- No, no!
- Escape! You must escape, Carmelita!
- No!
Escape now, Carmelita!
You must escape, Carmelita!
Miss Carmelita!
Thank God I found you.
You must get out of here, Miss.
- Don't let Mr. Leandro find you.
- Why?
He was the one who paid Mr. Raul
to kill Miss Josefina.
What?
He also captured Angelito
to force Mr. Juanito to admit
planning your sister's murder.
General!
- The woman is here!
- Wait!
Wait! What are you gonna do to Laura?
Don't hurt Laura, wait!
Don't you lay your hands on her!
Wait!
What are you -
Carmelita!
Are you alright?
Thank God you're alive.
Did they hurt you?
Are you in pain?
What are you gonna do to Laura?!
Carmelita.
Laura is a rebel!
Rebel?!
I know the truth!
You had Josefina killed
and you kidnapped Angelito!
How could you?!
Carmelita, there's no
truth to what you're saying.
What?...
Carmelita!
- Dear!
- Father!
Miss Carmelita?
Noche Buena is tonight.
Is there anything you want us to cook?
Maybe some caldereta.
Would Father eat with me?
I haven't
talked to him since I arrived here.
He's probably just resting.
Did you know?
Your father almost never
came home just to look for you.
Is he not mad at me anymore?
He was never mad at you.
He was just a bit hurt and upset.
Because you put Juanito first
instead of your family.
Did I act too selfishly?
Later,
your father has to go somewhere.
To thank General Leandro and his men.
For saving you.
You had Josefina killed
and you kidnapped Angelito!
Good morning, Don Alejandro.
Father.
Good morning.
Esmeralda already told me.
You can attend mass as long
as you're with her and Leandro.
Father.
Please listen to what I have to say.
It's not true that Juanito
was the mastermind
behind the death of Josefina.
Carmelita...
Stop defending Juanito.
But Father!
You won't expect who was
really behind Josefina's murder.
Who are you talking about?
It was Leandro.
That's enough, child.
Stop spewing those lies!
I know you just want to escape
your arranged marriage to Leandro
so that you and Juanito could be free!
But Father,
listen please.
I'm telling the truth.
Laura told me.
It's true
Leandro was the one behind Josefina's death
and we have to make a
plan to give her justice!
Carmelita!
I told you to stop.
Don't make up stories to taint
the name of the Flores family!
I know
you want to stop your
upcoming wedding to Leandro.
This is the last time
we'll talk about this.
Miss?
Do you want to stroll around
before heading to church?
Yes...
Let's go.
Miss, I apologize.
My knees aren't good for
walking long distances anymore.
Especially in places with so many people.
I'll just go by myself?
You won't be alone.
Someone's gonna be with you.
I didn't expect
Miss Esmeralda will be
the one who will help us.
The only way for me and Juanito
to see each other again.
Even in secret.
Don't worry.
Catapang believes it was Don
Alejandro's men who was responsible...
For the death
of Carding.
Why didn't you tell me about Angelito?
Why did you carry all the burden yourself?
Because I was worried Leandro
would pin everything on Don Alejandro.
You are aware of my father's involvement?
Why didn't you say anything? Why...
Why didn't you take
revenge against my father?
Because I do not want to hurt you.
Because I love you.
But I saw you and Mercedes close together.
We were just friends.
You're the only one in my heart.
Really?
Merry Christmas.
It's so beautiful here.
This tree
is the witness to our love.
That we can overcome anything...
And that no matter what
happens, we'll endure it together.
I love you.
Carmelita.
Huh?
Three different languages.
But all mean one thing.
I love you.
I love you too.
I will never forget this day.
First of January, 1892.
The day I finally told him
that I love him.
Eduardo and I knew Father
Orlando from San Alfonso.
When Eduardo helped Angelito
escape from Hacienda Flores...
He asked the Father
to help Angelito hide for awhile.
Where is Eduardo now?
Are they together with Maria?
They are together in an island.
I also intended to bring you
there when we decided to elope.
I'm sorry.
We saw you that night Eduardo
and Laura helped me escape.
We weren't able to stop Laura from
running to you and confessing everything.
We also witnessed the
guards executing her that night.
How did Eduardo know you
were captured by Leandro?
You traveled a long way
to reach Eduardo to ask for
help in rescuing my brother.
Why?
Brother...
I apologize for not
informing you earlier...
But Theresita and I are in love.
What?
How?
Since when?
It has been two months.
It happened when we were still in Bohol.
Please accept our relationship.
Angelito,
you are both still young.
You aren't supposed to
hold each other's hands.
And how about you?
We are of legal age.
And you are not.
You shouldn’t be courting or holding hands.
But it is not my intention...
To go between the two of you.
I'm happy for the both of you.
Carmelita, come.
Don't be afraid of Sampaguita.
Sampaguita.
Carmelita, come.
Sampaguita will not harm you.
Look, Sampaguita.
My love is afraid of you.
Alright then,
I will introduce you.
Sampaguita.
OMG.
The dog understands Spanish?
Sampaguita.
This is Carmelita.
The woman I love.
Carmelita,
this is Sampaguita.
My faithful pet.
I remember her.
But what is she doing here?
I asked Father Orlando to look after her
when my Father told me to get rid of her
during the Feast of San Alfonso.
The dinner your whole family attended.
So it was my fault why she
was taken away from Juanito.
Sampaguita!
Come!
Don't be afraid of Sampaguita.
Sampaguita is a good dog.
I know Sampaguita's a good dog.
She hasn't forgotten you even
though you've been apart for too long.
That's why I love her very much.
She's loyal and doesn't forget.
Isn't that right, Sampaguita?
No matter how long we've been apart.
That's how it is when you love each other.
Will I let this dog beat me?
Fine. We're friends now.
Come!
Sampaguita.
That's Carmelita.
Go on, she's nice.
I'm not afraid of you anymore, okay?
Whoever Juanito loves, I love too.
And if it's alright with
you, starting today...
If you'd let me,
I'll be your mother.
See?
I'm not afraid of you anymore.
How are you?
For Juanito,
it's like a dream I don't
want to wake up from.
But what happens next?
Is a nightmare I want to
slap myself awake from.
Carmelita.
I have been waiting for you,
but you were not in your room.
What the heck!?
What is she doing in my territory?
I already warned you not
to hurt my siblings again.
But you didn't listen.
Because of you,
Helena went away.
my brother Leandro is suffering.
You know,
You also know what's
Leandro been doing, right?
Be careful of me.
You don't know who you're dealing with.
You will regret this.
If I know, she just cursed me.
Whatever, bitch.
Juanito!?
That's just the first bullet.
Leandro!
So that you can't escape.
Leandro, I am begging you.
Just this once, please.
Leandro, don't.
Please, Leandro.
It seems like Leandro
couldn't do anything
to save you and your family.
Not for long,
the rebels will find out that
Juanito died because of you.
Carmelita...
I heard that Leandro
killed Juanito.
Forgive me, Carmelita.
No!
Miss!
Are you alright?
Did you have a nightmare?
You must be exhausted
from embroidering.
Me?
Embroidery?